# **Jase Cutler**

jasecutler@gmail.com 801-616-2422 https://github.com/cutlerjd

I am a Junior Web Developer experienced with Full Stack applications and working on teams. I have multiple years of experience in the IT field to solve business needs through utilizing IT tools and solutions.

Skills			Proficient			
JavaScript	React	HTML/CSS	JSON	MySQL	Mongo	Redux
Node.js	Express	Splunk	XML	JQuery	Linux	Regex

# Education

## The Iron Yard, Las Vegas, NV - 2017

- Certificate in Full Stack Development Three month immersion course
  - o Worked 60+ a week developing web apps and back-ends focusing on JavaScript
  - o Constructed Express back-ends utilizing RESTful APIs, MySQL and authentication
  - Built single page applications with React utilizing outside API's for data and form inputs and web components for navigation
  - Worked on teams to develop projects, and taught and explained programming concepts to others
  - Utilized software repositories (GitHub) to track and save changes on projects

### Utah Valley University - 2014

- Bachelors in Information Systems
  - Related course work:
    - Intro to System Administration Linux & Computer Programming C # (INFO 1200, 2200, 1510)

# Experience

# UNLV - IT Operations Analyst - 05/2015 - 07/2017

- Developed interactive dashboards to provide metrics and troubleshooting for the 2016 Presidential debates. Pulled in Twitter analytics to provide real-time reports during the debates for the UNLV Communications department, as well as syslog and security dashboards for IT technicians managing the debate floor.
- Worked on a research team that utilized machine learning and statistics to predict student success in classes within the first month of class to increase retention. Responsible for verifying incoming data, building integrations, and education on using Splunk machine learning. Built custom reports within Splunk according to customer needs.
- Implemented Problem Management for Network Operations Center and the UNLV IT division. Wrote the technical
  documents and reviewed procedures to ensure long term issues that arose were communicated to campus in a
  consistent and concise manner.

# Stewart Title - Client Services Technician - 08/2014 - 05/2015

- Created new backup procedures for the regional offices of Nevada across four offices.
- Developed a new wiki for procedures done by technicians across the national company.
- Worked with many other techs to set up multiple new offices, including racking and setting up network equipment and workstations for hundreds of employees.

#### Utah Valley University - Support Technician II - 05/2013 - 05/2014

- Worked on a team that improved processes of imaging lab computers and worked to remove hours of configuration time needed for each computer.
- Developed reporting system using SCCM and SQL to show what software was available in each lab to aid in scheduling of classes.